In the previous lecture, we learned about the planning and reasoning capability of AI agents.
Now, let's go and take a look at the demo.
Now, for this demo, I've created a micro-cool AI agent and everything else pretty much remains the same.
So, just instead of going on a skiing trip, maybe Joe wants to go on a five-day beach vocation.
And from the AI agent capability perspective, I have just kept two functionality.
One, the agent can make a call to the HR system to check the leave balance of the employee.
And second, it can book a hotel room based on the user request.
So, I've just simplified it a little bit so that it's easier to understand.
Now, let's take a look at the questions that we're going to ask.
So, we're going to ask two questions.
First one, book a hotel room for me employee ID is 2525 and if my leave balance is more than five days,
then book the hotel with following details.
Now, for this question, you can see agent has to do three things.
First, it has to go to the HR system and retrieve the vacation days for this employee.
Then it has to make the decision whether the leave balance is less than or more than five days.
If it is more than five days, then it has to make an API call to the hotel booking site
and book the hotel room.
But if the leave balance is less than five days, then it has to come back and tell the user
that it cannot go ahead and book the hotel because the leave balance is less than five days.
Now, let's go ahead and run this query.
Now, I'm on the micro cool AI agent that has been built.
So, I have a UI here and let me just pose this question.
Now, before I execute this query, let's take a look at the leave balance table which gives me
a details about the leave balance for this employee to 5125 and the leave balance is only four days.
So, when I run this query, I should get a response from the agent saying that it cannot book a
hotel room because the leave balance is not more than five.
So, let me just go ahead and run this.
So, now it has come back with the response unfortunate to your leave balance is four days,
which is not sufficient to book a room for five nights as requested.
So, this is correct.
Now, let's go ahead and ask another question where I say book a hotel room
for this employee if the leave balance is more than three days.
And which is true, we have four days leave balance as we just saw.
So, let me just copy this and now let me go ahead and run this query.
So, let me just do a run.
Now, I have got a response with the booking ID ending in 5 EC.
So, this is my booking ID.
Let's go ahead and check the hotel booking room table and see if this entry is there.
Let me just do a refresh and I have a booking ID here ending in 5 EC.
And we have Jane Doe and number 9 says 3 and these were the details we had provided.
Now, let's take a look at the traces and planning capability of the AI agent through which
it reached this conclusion.
So, let me just click on traces.
So, we have three traces here step one, step two and step three.
So, first I will just click on trace step one.
So, in trace step one we have model invocation input.
So, what is the input that is going to the large language model that is driving the AI agent.
And here are some configuration parameters for the LLM then.
So, next you can see the text here which determines what is the prompt that will go to the
large language model driving the AI agent.
Now, remember the large language model does not have any context or memory on what kind of agent
you are or what are your key roles and responsibilities.
So, that is the context we provide first.
So, we are saying you are an agent that can check the leave balance based on employee ID
and book a hotel room and so on.
Then if you scroll down, we are providing it some more guidelines around what are the tools
and API calls etcetera that you can make and we will discuss this in the next lecture.
Finally, towards the end we are just providing the user input.
So, what we have here.
So, we are saying book a hotel room with employee ID this and if my leave balance is more than
three then book a hotel room with these details.
And then based on this user input, the LLM is coming out with an output.
And what is the output look like?
So, this is the raw response.
It says, okay, let me check your leave balance first and then proceed with the hotel booking.
And then you have the thinking tag to check the employee's leave balance.
I need to call employee leave balance function with the provided employee ID.
And then again thinking tag, let me call this particular API leave balance with parameters employee ID
and then it's coming out with a rationale saying, okay, to check the employee's leave balance
I need to call the employee leave balance function.
And then it goes ahead and makes that API call.
So, API path slash leave balance and it provides all these parameters.
And then it gets an observation and we are discussed.
Observation means an output from an external entity to an agent.
And in this case, it is the leave balance API.
It is the leave balance DynamoDB table.
And now it has got a response.
So, it has leave balance is for for employee ID and name is Rahul Thrysel and so on.
Now, let's take a look at the step two.
So, it successfully executed step one where it is where it has got the leave balance.
So, in the leave balance again, it's going to send the output.
It has got a leave balance to the large language model that is driving the agent and you
have the model invocation input.
So, it remains pretty much same.
But the only thing that has been appended this time is the the previous information it got
on what was the leave balance for 2 5 1 2 0 5 from the previous step.
So, it's saying my leave balance is 4.
And then we have the model invocation output.
So, this is the output I get from the large language model.
So, it says thinking tag, the employee has 4 days of leave balance which is more than required
3 days because in the query we had said if my leave balance is more than 3 days,
then only book the hotel room.
So, now we can see how it is thinking and we have not provided any predefined logic.
So, this is the logic it's applying on its own.
So, this is the reasoning capability of the LLM that it is applying here.
So, I can proceed ahead with the booking hotel room with the previous details.
And these are the details that we had provided on check-in date and so on.
And then it shows the rationale the employee has 4 days of leave and it's pretty much the same
without those tags.
And then it goes ahead and calls the hotel booking API.
So, slash book hotel room and then it says you know what tool it's going to use.
It's going to use a lambda function in this case and it provides all the parameters
such as check-in date, number of flights, guest room and so on.
And then it gets an observation.
So, now let's go ahead and look at the trace 3.
And in the trace 3 again it will send a request to the model.
So, here you see the model invocation input and here is the prompt.
So, it's pretty similar if I just scroll down towards the end.
So, it provides the leave balance which it had provided in the previous call as well.
But then it provides some additional information saying that employers 4 days of leave balance
which is more than a quite 3.
Then it provides some details around which API it needs to call to book the hotel,
what is the name of the guest and so on.
And then you get the model invocation output.
And here is the raw response which says your hotel booking is confirmed,
following details check-in date and so on and it provides the booking confirmation ID.
And then you have the final observation where it says your hotel booking is confirmed
and this is what we have got here.
Hopefully it's clear to you now how it breaks down the problem into multiple steps.
And then executes each step and then it can also replan if required.
Okay that's pretty much it from this lecture.
I'll see you in the next lecture.
Thank you.